Hello and welcome back. Now that we know, the underlying
大家好 欢迎回来 现在我们已经知道了
framework of non-vocal means, let's just demo it in real time.
非局部均值 (non-local means) 的基本内容 让我们来实时演示一下
Non-local means denoising works using the resources in the image processing online
例子中的非局部均值降噪采用在线图像处理学报网 (Image Processing On Line Journal) 上的资源实现
journal. This is a website that I have provided a
我已经把这个网站的链接
link in their webpage for this class, is a journal that has a lot of online
放到了课程网页上 这个网站上有大量在线的
algorithms for image processing. And I strongly suggest that you visit it
图像处理算法 我强烈建议你访问这里
if you want to play with a lot of the state of the art in image processing.
可以在这里尝试许多前沿的图像处理技术
So the journal has first a full description of the algorithm. It has also
网站首先描述了整个算法
code that you can download and use in your own computer, but also has an online
并提供了可下载的代码 代码可在自己计算机上使用 还有在线演示
demo and that's what we are going to do next.
这也就是我们接下来要做的事
You can upload your own images, or you can basically use the images already
你可以上传自己的图片 或者使用网站提供的图片
available on the website, just to illustrate and to help you understand the
这些图片只是用来演示 并帮助你更好地理解算法
algorithm better. So let's just pick this image, for
那么我们选这张图作为例子
example. And it's here.
它在这里
And we're going to run the algorithm. We're going to add some noise to the
我们将运行这个算法 我们先给这张图加点噪声
image to see how non-local means will de-noise that, and we're going to ask you
看看非局部均值如何降噪 然后点击运行
to run. So, now it's running, we see this.
现在算法正在运行 我们能看到这个
This algorithm can be made to run very fast, but now it's running on a server
这个算法可以运行得很快 但现在它运行在服务器上
and it's running on an implementation that is not optimized for that.
而且没有对此做相应的优化
But here we have the result. So we see, let's just illustrate the
不过我们还是得到了结果 我们来看一下细节
details. We see here is the noisy image.
这个是噪声图像
Basically, the original image with the other noise, and now we see the de-noised
它是原来的图像加上了噪声 现在看到的是降噪后的图像
image. Again, this is the noisy image, this is
再来一遍 这是噪声图像
the de-noised image, and this is the original.
这是降噪后的图像 这是原来的图像
So we see that there are differences, but certainly the de-noised image is much
我们可以看出有差别 但显然降噪后的图像比
better than the noisy image. Now, we can actually see the difference
噪声图像要好很多 现在我们能看到
between the de-noised image and the original image.
降噪后的图像与原来的图像的差别
Once again, this is the noisy image, the de-noised image, the original image,
再来一次 这是噪声图像 这是降噪后的图像 这是原来的图像
and the difference. They just run with a different image.
以及两者相差的图像 我们换别的图来运行一下
So let's just select a new input here, and we can pick a different image, for
我们在这里选一个新的输入 我们可以选一张不同的图
example, these dice. And we can pick a different level of
比如这个骰子图 我们可以选不同程度的噪声
noise, and just put a lot of noise to see what happens here, and then let's just
加上较大的噪声看看会发生什么 接着我们来点击运行
run it. Once again, while this is running,
趁它在运行 再重申一下
remember, the goal of non-local means is to look for regions,
非局部均值的目标是找到一些区域
say, okay, if I want to de-noise this region, I'm going to look for similar
如果我想给这个区域降噪 我会在周围寻找
regions around and average them. The larger the noise, the more the
相近的区域并对它们求平均 噪声越大
algorithm will take, because it's goign to try to average more and more patches
算法所用到的区域就越多 因为它要设法对更多的小块求平均
to help us reduce the noise, the noise even further.
以此来帮助我们进一步地降低噪声
So here is, again, the noisy image the algorithm has finished.
算法运行完了 我们又看到了噪声图像
This is the noisy. This is the de-noised image.
这是噪声图像 这是降噪后的图像
This is the original, and this is the difference.
这是原来的图像 而这个图像显示出它们的差异
So we think it has done a very, very good job in de-noising this image.
这张图像的降噪效果非常好
Noisy? De-noise.
噪声图像 降噪后的图像
Noisy, de-noise. Original image and the difference.
噪声图像 降噪后的图像 原来的图像 以及差异的图像
This image doesn't have a lot of texture. And that's why these type of algorithms
这张图没有很多的纹理 这也是为什么这类算法
work really, really, well. There, when there is a lot of texture,
能够处理得非常好 当图像有很多纹理时
the algorithm still works very well, but for every denoise image denoising
算法依旧表现得很好 但对所有的图像降噪算法来说
algorithm, dealing with texture is a bit more difficult.
处理纹理会比较难
So let's just conclude this by showing this once again.
让我们再看一遍作为总结
Noisy, de-noise, original, and difference.
噪声图像 降噪后的图像 原来的图像 以及差异的图像
And once again, you can just go into the ipo.im website and play with this or any
再提一下 你可以上 ipol.im 网站试试这个示例
other algorithm that is available there, and you can upload your own images and
或者网站提供的任何一个算法 你可以上传你自己的图像
see how it works. Thank you, and see you in the next video.
看它如何处理 谢谢大家 下个视频再见 // 果壳教育无边界字幕组 | nblintao |  luoyetx | 小白_远游